### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/sherleen-lee (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Excellent communicator in crossfuctional, multicultural teams

Strong critical thinking and creative analysis

Impactful data visualizations

## Languages

Chinese (Limited Working)
Indonesian (Full Professional)
English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Beta Alpha Psi Lifetime Member CCNA: Introduction to Networks Google Analytics for Beginners pandas Essential Training

# Sherleen Lee

Business Analytics Professional | Global Expertise in Business Intelligence with Interest in CPG and Retail | Ability to create innovative solutions | Experience in cross-functional teams | Python, SQL, and Tableau

Pasadena, California, United States

## Summary

Sherleen Lee is a Business Analytics Professional with global work experience spanning diverse industries, including Luxury Goods, Consumer Packaged Goods, Consulting, Healthcare, Aerospace, and Nonprofit. Sherleen's expertise encompasses skills and knowledge in the realms of business intelligence, data mining, big data analytics, and cost accounting. With a passion for leveraging data to drive strategic decisions and optimize operations, Sherleen is dedicated to delivering valuable insights and solutions in the Consumer Packaged Goods Industry.

## Experience

STEAM:CODERS

Data Analyst

August 2022 - May 2023 (10 months)

Pasadena, California, United States

Collected and visualized demographic data from multiple organizations for grant reports

Collaborated on building a data pipeline

Designed best practices to collect, clean, and migrate data

Utilized Google Sheets and Snowflake for warehousing

#### Boeing

Boeing Collaboration Text Mining Project January 2022 - May 2022 (5 months)

Collaborated on a Named Entity Recognition model to automate labeling in aircraft maintenance records.

Designed visuals in Python and Tableau to present results that management would later leverage in its proprietary projects.

Presented results to Boeing senior management on a bi-weekly basis.

Healthmetryx Data Analyst April 2021 - June 2021 (3 months)

Remote

Assisted in the development of a dashboard app that collected and analyzed data via the cloud.

Designed visuals within Tableau to interpret respiratory data for prescriptive analytics.

Presented results and actionable insights in a presentation to investors and intellectual property lawyers.

Foresightbyte Analytica
Data Analyst
January 2021 - April 2021 (4 months)
Remote

Collaborated with a team to understand a luxury client's global counterfeiting data.

Developed business intelligence dashboards using Tableau to communicate insights from live datasets, providing the client with deeper context on counterfeiting instances.

Co-designed the development of an app that tracks mental and physical wellbeing scores via smartwatches.

PT Asia Paramita Indah Accounting Intern June 2019 - August 2019 (3 months) Indonesia

Created quarter-end accounts receivable packages in preparation for internal audit.

Designed KPI dashboards using pivot tables in support of strategic business decisions for one of the largest fast-moving consumer goods distributors in Indonesia.

# Education

University of Southern California

Master of Science - MS, Business Analytics · (August 2023)

California State Polytechnic University-Pomona

Computer Information Systems, Business Intelligence; Accounting · (2019 - 2022)

Pasadena City College
Associate of Science - AS, Business Administration and Management,
General · (2018 - 2019)